Chan Xue Li

cxuelisit@gmail.com | (+65) 84288217 | Portfolio: https://cxueli5.github.io/chanxueli/ | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/xue-li/

Looking for full-time job opportunities / internships for fresh graduates

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Hello! I am a Computing Science graduate at SIT-UofG and a Business Information Technology graduate at SP. Over the course of my academic journey, I have cultivated a diverse skill set and acquired valuable knowledge through my projects and my experiences in various industries such as the media industry (SPH) and e-commerce industry (E-Speed). I am passionate about working with people because they are the reason businesses exist and together with technology, I want to help businesses with their customer experience and together we can make this world a better place!

SKILLS

Teamwork, Adaptability, Communication, Empathy, Problem-Solving, Web Development, UI UX Design, HTML, CSS, Svelte, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, React, Node.js, GitHub, Python, SQL Server, mySQL, MongoDB, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe XD, Figma, Machine Learning, Social Media Marketing, SEO

EXPERIENCES

Singapore Press Holdings (SPH - The Straits Times)

AUG 2023 - APR 2024

Data Visualisation Developer Intern

- Worked in a team of 5 local and international developers from Brazil, Poland and Ukraine using front-end framework
 (Svelte) and UI design tools (Figma) to develop interactive news article for the Straits Times. Projects include a SG Food
 map website which includes recommendations from ST food journalists, and an anagram quiz game for Taylor Swift week
 in SG
- Created promotional images such as designing social media thumbnails for ST weekly publishes for Cartoons of the Week, Week in Pictures and Home in Focus, and published the articles on ST social media platforms such as Facebook and X. These images were designed using **Adobe Illustrator** and **Adobe Photoshop**
- Collaborated with a total of 8 international and local designers to create UI designs such as designing how the anagram
 game for Taylor Swift should be played and sought user feedback by testing the game experience with our colleagues.
 These designs were designed using Figma and Adobe XD

E-Speed Stabilizing Network Technology Pte. Ltd.

MAY 2022 - AUG 2022

Software Developer Intern

Took initiative to self-learn C#, NET, MVC framework with Microsoft SQL Server and redesigned an educational website
which offers students an opportunity to study abroad in countries such as Australia and New Zealand, obtaining
developer's acknowledgement of the good work

Born in Colour MAR 2020 – SEP 2020

Digital Marketing Intern

- Revamped blog page with search engine optimization which led to an increase in search rankings on Google (4th for Korean furniture). This was done by adding additional keywords and introducing tags to blog posts so that it makes it easier for users to find what they need, and improve the company's Google search rankings
- Enhanced website interface (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) to be more informative such as including directions to our physical stores, adding more pictures of the products from various angles, adding more information to FAQ based on customers' feedback in-store, improving staff's efficiency to address more sales specific enquiries which saved time and increased sales by 90% compared to past year sales
- Introduced, designed and launch promotional posters for featured products such as adding products featured in Korean dramas to capture customers' attention, which increased customers enquiries by 95% about the featured products

Hangman Telebot Web-application Game

• Led a team of 5 students from various courses in SIT such as nursing and animation to develop a hangman webapplication game which can be accessed via a telebot in Telegram chatting application (self-learn), achieving 2nd best in user experience chosen by TikTok front-end developers

Final Year Project (UOB)

NOV 2021

Branch Service Portal Web-application

Worked in a team of 5 students from my diploma and collaborated with UOB to develop a branch service portal for
customers to complete specific banking transactions and self-services for bank related enquiries, resulting in customer's
ease of self-service and reduce waiting time at bank dealer counters

EDUCATION

Singapore Institute of Technology (SIT-UofG)

SEP 2021 - SEP 2024

• Bachelor of Science with Honours in Computing Science

Singapore Polytechnic (SP)

APR 2018 - APR 2021

• Diploma in Business Information Technology – GPA 3.63, Edusave Certificate of Academic Achievement 2020